[Music]
s I'm going to talk about Joo once again
but
first Story
Time chapter 1
Anita the most famous bigot in American
LGBT history is a woman called Anita
Bryant this is her
story 1977 was not a good time to be gay
is it ever really a good time to be gay
in 1969 The Stonewall riots forced gay
rights into National Consciousness the
first Pride parades were held in the
summer of 1970 and in 1973 the American
Psychiatric association Declassified
homosexuality as a mental disorder but
only after gay activists disrupted their
conference and shouted gay conversion
therapy is torture we have abnormal
urges and we will not be
silenced because that's the only way to
get anything done in this country you
have to be super annoying about about it
they give you no choice on January 18th
1977 Dade County Florida known for such
popular cities as Miami approved a law
that added the phrase affectional or
sexual preference to its
non-discrimination ordinance effectively
Banning housing and employment
discrimination on the basis of sexual
orientation and it was just then as
things seemed to be getting better that
Anita Bryant made her little appearance
Anita Bryant missed Oklahoma Anita
Bryant is a native Oklahoma who once had
a career as a pop singer beauty queen
and spokeswoman for the Florida Citrus
commission to the Florida Sunshine tree
my twins love 100% orange juice from
Florida any time of day orange juice
from Florida it isn't just for breakfast
anymore orange juice with natural
vitamin C from the Florida
Sunshine she was known for these TV
commercials with the tagline a day
without orange juice is like a day
without Sunshine breakfast without
orange juice is like a day without
Sunshine cute when Anita heard her
pastor speak about this
non-discrimination ordinance she felt a
Divine disturbance in her heart how
touching according to the word of God
it's an
Abomination uh to practice homosexuality
as a mother she would not stand for this
so Anita wrote a letter to the county
commissioner saying as a concerned
mother of four children I am most
definitely against this ordinance
amendment I have never condoned nor
taught my children discrimination
against anyone but if this ordinance
amendment is allowed to become law you
will in fact be infringing upon my
rights and discriminating against me as
a citizen and a mother to teach my
children God's moral code as stated in
the Holy scriptures Anita kill your
shitty child when the amendment passed
Anita created a campaign for its repeal
the save our children Coalition which
sponsored provocative tv ads in implying
that gay people are degenerates who ruin
communities and seduce children the
campaign has been vicious with
television commercials the Savar
children group is appealing to parental
anxieties saying gays will F their
homosexuality before impressionable
children the Orange Bowl Parade Miami's
gift to the nation wholesome
entertainment but in San Francisco when
they take to the streets it's a parade
of homosexuals men hugging other men
cavorting with little boys save our
children sparked the first organized
backlash to gay rights in the United
States escalating the conflict into a
national controversy on one side were
the gay rights activists who argued that
non-discrimination was a matter of human
rights on the opposing side Anita Bryant
argued that the non-discrimination
ordinance would give special privileges
to homosexuals we all believe in human
rights but we don't believe uh human
rights that would corrupt our children
or for individuals to have special
privileges that would go against the
constitutional rights of normal America
as long as they don't want to flaunt
their homosexuality they have equal
rights the same as anyone else in other
words gay people already have equal
rights just as long as they stay in the
closet and don't do anything gay that's
very helpful thank you so much Anita for
standing up for our right to be gay in
secret as long as they do their job and
do not want to come out of the closet
and force their homosexuality uh on me
in the areas of of business or in the
schools they can they can live their
life and I'm we're not going out after
their jobs or trying to get them out of
their teaching JS Anita also argued that
allowing flaunting homosexuals to teach
children was tantamount to gay
recruitment just biologically the God
made mother so that we could reproduce
homosexuals cannot reproduce
biologically but they have to reproduce
by recruiting our children it's the
exact same argument that's being used
today by rightwing politicians who claim
that queer people are groomers stop
confusing our babies with your groomer
gender ideologue this wicked book me and
Earl and the dying girl sexually
indoctrinated with Wicked vile books and
she believes in traditional marriage
between a man and a woman and in that
book it talked about two moms stay away
from the children creep or you will
regret it people should definitely arm
themselves I agree with that the
Democrats are the party of pedophiles
the Democrats are the party of of
teachers uh Elementary School teachers
trying to trying to transition their
Elementary School age children and
convince them they're a different gender
they're just evil people and they want
to Grom kids yeah they're recruiting if
you don't know what furries are it's
where school children dress up as
animals cats or dogs during the school
day they meow and they bark what a great
country we live in I love it so much gay
people around around the country rallied
against Anita Bryant and save our
children there was a national boycott of
Florida orange juice with many gay bars
taking screwdrivers off the menu and
replacing them with an apple juice and
vodka cocktail called an Anita Bryant
let's make one now forgot my cocktail
measure so I'm just going to have to
eyeball this just a dash of apple juice
give it a
[Music]
stir needs a
garnish stunning I mean it's not as good
as a screwdriver but if I was in the 70s
I would have thrown back so many of
these goddamn things out of pure spite
there's a story that Troy Perry the
founder of the gay affirming
Metropolitan Community Church was on a
transcontinental flight and when the
attendant put a glass of orange trees on
his tray he said take that away I'm a
homosexual at gay pride marches in 1977
and 78 anti- Anita Bryant slogans
featured prominently on t-shirts signs
and buttons Anita Bryant sucks Orange es
a day without lesbians is like a day
without Sunshine true and meanwhile
Anita's campaign inspired more anti-gay
legislation including bans on gay
adoption and same-sex marriage both of
which passed in the Florida Senate as
well as the failed Briggs initiative in
California which would have forced
public schools to fire gay teachers so
Anita Bryant was worse than a bigot she
was an influential bigot but she may
also have helped to unify and Galvanize
gay activists by providing them with a
common enemy according to historian
lilan faderman Anita Bryant created
fervent activists out of those who'd
previously been content simply to enjoy
their Newfound freedoms faderman cites
Eric Hoffer's observation that a mass
movement can get along fine without a
God but it won't get along at all
without a devil for gay people all over
the country Anita Bryant became that
devil I think that she is ring the
community together like I have never
seen before there's no way I could have
done it on my own so even though she
succeeded her initial goal to repeal the
non-discrimination ordinance there is no
question that in the long term Anita
Bryant was the loser she took a lot of
L's rip that must be super hard for her
for the short remainder of her career
gay activists protested her events they
shut down the tour for her book about
how persecuted she was by the militant
homosexual and they succeeded in turning
public opinion against Anita Bryant to
the point that she became virtually
unemployable in mainstream entertainment
and helped that she came across as kind
of a judgmental prude that even hip
straight people didn't want to be
associated with our top story tonight
Anita Bryant former mediocre actress and
orange juice promoter performed coetus
in public yesterday and campaign to
promote heterosexuality we don't serve
orange juice anymore like she famously
told Playboy magazine why do you think
the homosexuals are called fruits it's
because they eat the forbidden fruit of
the Tree of Life God referred to men as
trees and because the homosexuals eat
the forbidden fruit which is male sperm
oh my God like the woman is heterosexual
cringe this is how you lose the culture
War so let's
allice around and of course there was
the famous incident where a gay activist
smashed a banana cream pie in Anita's
face during a TV appearance and went
into a place called Northport Virginia
and were met with protest and um um all
kinds of problems and uh uh
every security agent security agent no
no let him stay let him stay well at
least it's a fruit pie Miami Dade County
finally reinstated the
non-discrimination ordinance in 1998 and
they added gender identity to its
Protections in 2014 in 2021 Anita took
another metaphorical pie to the face
when her granddaughter Sarah Green came
out as gay announcing her marriage to a
woman in publicly struggling with
whether to even invite her grandmother
to the ceremony it's very hard to argue
with someone who thinks that like an
integral part of your identity is just
uh an evil
delusion that it is Sarah that it is so
that's the story of Anita Bryant as
students of LGBT history know it but
isn't it a bit one-sided wasn't there a
lot of toxicity on both sides the Anita
Bryant forces talk of absolute truth and
morality gay leaders are equally
dogmatic about human rights a plague on
both the houses isn't it cruel even to
slur Anita as a bigot and a homophobe in
fact isn't it possible that Anita Bryant
was the real
victim oh no oh
no I can't do this anymore I'm eating my
pie I'm eating my godamn pie chapter 2
The Witch Trials of Anita Bri
God help us all the mainstream media
would have us believe that Anita Bryant
is a so-called homophobe some kind of
hateful bigot but isn't this just an
authoritarian tactic used to silence
valid concerns mothers in this country
are worried about their children going
to school to be taught by perverts how
can we be so sure that the militant
homosexuals weren't the real Bots isn't
it possible that Anita Bryant was the
first victim of cancel culture of dare I
say it wokeism well no that's the
dumbest thing I've ever heard in my
entire life but suppose that you're an
idiot and suppose that that's the
narrative you wanted to promote well
what would be your argument I mean if
someone put a gun to my head and forced
me to make that argument I'd probably
say something like this Anita Bryant
lived a difficult life in 1940 she was
born into brutal poverty in rural
Oklahoma her parents divorced when she
was just 2 years old the same year she
made her singing debut at the Baptist
Church parts of my childhood I blocked
out because it hurts too much I guess I
was happiest when I was 8 years old and
my parents were remarried and I was
baptized and came to know Christ as my
personal savior her father abandoned the
family again when she was 12 it was real
painful and it just about killed my
mother she was a very submissive wife
she was too submissive and it angered me
she let my dad step all over her because
of him I think I went through life for a
long time hating all men Anita described
her most intense adolescent memory as a
feeling of intense ambition a Relentless
drive to succeed at doing well the thing
I loved Glory Glory
hallelu his truth his
Maring but Anita's ambition conflicted
with her submissive role as a
traditional Christian woman in 1960
Anita married Bob Green Miami's top disc
jockey only after he relentlessly
badgered her into it this is what
heterosexuals do
fellas green was allegedly a controlling
and abusive husband feminist Andrea
dworin claims green manipulated Bryant
with a cruelty nearly unmatched in
Modern Love Stories and Anita
rationalized the abuse saying despite
our sometimes violent scraps I love him
for it but While submitting to her
husband and raising four children an was
still able to build the career she'd
always wanted by the 1970s she was on
the payroll of big orange juice earning
half a million dollars a year enough to
move her family into a 27 room Spanish
mansion on biscane Bay so Anita Bryant
struggled all her life for her success
did she really deserve to lose it all
just because she took a stand for
something she believed in andita
Bryant's role as a leader in the
campaign against homosexuals may be
hurting her campaign to sell orange
jeice are you being black bowled well
it's uh it's it looks that way it's it's
worse than that we're being threatened
and uh there's all kinds of harassment
even with my job with Florida Citrus I
haveed of
to and all children against being
recruited by homosexuals her entire life
had become a series of catastrophes
she'd been dropped as spokesperson by
the orange growers she had been dropped
as a commentator on the Orange Bowl
Parade she lost a television show
contract her bookings dropped
drastically it destroys theam I
have to ENT
and my fellow Americans because I dared
to speak out for straight and normal
America no one has paid as dearly as
neita Bryant for taking a public stand
on something she believed in I remember
lying in the bed in my my mother's house
in a fetal position and wanting to die
gay activists in the 1970s didn't
exactly limit their tactics to polite
debate in the free Marketplace of ideas
stop now stop now stop homosexuals
started fighting back the gays formed
new groups and picketed the performers
public appearances forcing her to cancel
a few gay activists routinely compared
Anita to Adolf H they created pases of
her orange juice slogan they blamed her
for hate crimes they burned her in
effigy they disrupted events she was
involved in they printed toilet paper
with her face on it some sent a death
threats or they mailed her rotting
oranges dead cockroaches human excrement
see this is how you canceled people
before phones instead of [ __ ] posting
you would simply mail actual human [ __ ]
through the United States Postal Service
neither snow nor rain nor heat nor Gloom
of night an's husband pleaded to
supporters how would you men feel if you
opened a letter and there was a photo of
your wife's head superimposed on some
other female nude body in the most lewd
and shocking sexual act you can imagine
I can imagine quite a lot I do think it
would be fair to say that a lot of the
rhetoric did take on a misogynistic tone
lilan faderman recounts that lesbians
particularly lesbian feminists abhor the
sexist terms that were being used to
characterize Anita Bryant [ __ ] and
[ __ ] gay men called her the harassment
escalated to the point where Anita had
to cancel her book tour due to
demonstrations and bomb threats from gay
activists and of course there was the
pie so much for the the tolerant mine
Society it's kind of a deep cut well
something to entertain the Boomer queers
gay activists claimed to stand for human
rights but what about Anita's rights to
free speech I wish I had some literal
pearls to clutch civil libertarian Nat
hentoff wrote in his 1992 book free
speech for me but not for thee that the
orange juice boycott reminded him of a
little thing called
McCarthyism have you ever considered
that being prog gay is quite similar to
being anti-gay and that both are
opinions as Anita tells it she and her
foot soldiers of God were the victims of
sinister gay Carpet Baggers the foot
soldiers were Housewives and mothers
religious and Civic leaders in
opposition to a well organized highly
financed and politically militant group
of homosexual activists We Were cast as
bigots haters discriminators and deniers
of basic human rights and all of this
happened because we were sincerely
concerned for our children and our
community so Anita's version of the
story is that she and a handful of
well-intentioned christian mothers were
cast as bigots by a highly funded Mafia
of gay extremists all because they had a
few Teensy tiny concerns about the
militant homosexual cavorting with
little boys cavorting with little boys
is it really fair to call this woman a
bigot until fade County ordinance Anita
was a registered Democrat and considered
herself a liberal and she never said
that she hated G people or wanted them
dead in fact she even said that she
loves homosexuals I love homosexuals if
you can believe that I love them enough
to tell them the truth because I know
that there is hope for the homosexuals
that if they're willing to uh turn from
uh sin the same as any individual that
uh that they can be ex homosexuals the
same as there can be an ex murderer an
ex thief or ex anybody she loves
homosexuals because they can change just
like murderers would a bigot have said
that just about mcfucking had it Anita
was so kind-hearted she even said that
she related to the homosexual I can
relate to the homosexual because I've
had emotional scars in my own life I
really felt the rejection of my father
and that is one of the things that maybe
lead someone going into homosexuality
look I don't hate homosexuals that's the
truth no matter what they think of my
motives I've always said I love The
Sinner but I hate the sin wow what an
empath you know I actually think it's
really Noble how she's able to project
all of her own emotional baggage onto
the marginalized group whose rights
she's trying to take
away okay so we've given a fair hearing
to both sides to many sides we've
considered all the evidence now let's
suppose there's no longer a gun to my
head and ask did Anita Bryant really
deserve that pie to the face well yes
obviously look the point of trying to
make here is that it's possible to take
genuine virtues like Nuance empathy and
impartiality and to twist them into
[ __ ] up apologia for horrible
oppressive Behavior if you play this
game long enough you can essentially
explain away the entire concept of
bigotry and conclude that in reality
there are no bigots there's only
tragically misunderstood people with
difficult childhoods and valid concerns
cruy demonized by militant activists
defaming and silencing them with such
reputation ruining slurs as homophobe
now because you viewers are smart media
literate people you understand framing
so you already know that I'm about to
compare aita Bryant to JK Rowling in
case you didn't know JK
rolling JK Rowling is a popular author
who used to write Whimsical stories
about wizard school but who now writes B
books about transvesti serial killers
masturbating into stolen panties because
she's lost her godamn mind Lo ho ho dear
readers Christ what a
nightmare Chapter 3 The Witch Trials of
JK Rowling all right kids it's transing
time last year I agreed to be a guest on
a podcast about JK rolling hosted by
Megan Phelps rooper an escape from the
westbo Baptist Church the notorious hate
group from topa Kansas most known for
protesting the funerals of soldiers with
signs that say God hates God and me both
I'm tired of you people JK Illy the
westbo Baptist Church is one of the most
famous homophobic hate groups in the
world in a way I'm like a lifelong fan
of these people I've watched all the
Louis through documentaries I went to a
counter protest in 2010 I remember how
when I was in high school the westbo
Baptist Church was like the one thing
that conservatives and liberals could
agree on because they hated the troops
and the gays essentially the two genders
of 2006 but let's not pretend that the
westro Baptist Church is all bad okay
when Megan was at westbo she used to do
these amazing Lady Gaga parodies about
how the gays are going to hell which to
this day I am a big fan of what did you
say you think God loves your praying he
hates all you do cuz you love
fornicating for it's perfect I love it
play it at my funeral stop praying stop
praying God will not hear you anymore
you C the boys and the girls to be proud
for forever go you just keep pushing on
to the hell where you will forever Megan
left the westbo Baptist Church in 2012
after a crisis of Faith precipitated by
a power struggle within the church
she wrote about all this in her book
unfollow which is honestly a pretty
interesting account of deconversion and
the circumstances that lead someone to
leaving a hate group Megan contacted me
for her podcast because I had criticized
JK ring in a video a couple years ago
now you may be wondering why would I
think that a person who's been carrying
a godh hates sign most of her life would
be the correct person to lead an
international conversation about the
intricacies of LGBT issues because I'm
an idiot happy basically I agreed to the
podcast because it's a pretty
irresistible pitch a former member of
the westbo Baptist Church wants to
mediate a conversation between me and
the author of Harry Potter would you say
no to that
maybe if you're smart last month the
podcast was announced in an essay by
Megan titled The Witch Trials of JK
rolling obviously attend ous framing
that posits Joo as the target of an
irrational trans Witch Hunt the essay
included a teaser quote from Rowling
complaining that she's been profoundly
misunderstood as well as a photo of an
angry trans mob holding a rotten hell
rolling sign juxtaposed with an image of
conservative Christians burning Harry
Potter books in the early 2000s this did
not bode well so I disavowed the podcast
on Twitter because I didn't want my my
name lending legitimacy to some kind of
unearned JK rolling Redemption tour this
caused Megan's mom surely to quote tweet
me calling me a bigot against God I mean
God is one of the most vulnerable
minorities there's only one of him and
he could really use your help surely I
said in these tweets that I felt used
which that is how I felt but ultimately
I need to take full responsibility for
my involvement in this the thing about
about being a guest on a documentary
like this is you honestly have no idea
what the final product is going to be
like so the decision to participate is
always a leap of faith and I can't
really say that Megan misled me there
were red flags from the beginning and I
ignored them because I was projecting my
own hopes onto the situation you know
it's a compelling story i' liked to the
idea that this famous former bigot could
talk some sense into a famous current
bigot we all love a good Redemption Arc
and I started my career der radicalizing
the alt right that's something I've
moved away from but there's still part
of me that wants to see the best in
people and to believe that people can
change if you just talk to them and make
a good enough
argument maybe my wishful thinking was
that because Megan left
westbo that must mean that she must
understand the intricacies of anti-lgbt
bigotry right and despite no evidence
for this My Hope was that Megan would
act as the trans Ally and could be
really effective at confronting Joo
about all the transphobic stuff she says
right wrong I'm Megan phes rer and these
are the Witch Trials of JK
[Music]
ruling the witch trial of JK Rowling is
more than 7 hours of apologetics for JKR
the podcast presents rolling as a
complex Humane heroic figure with an
inspiring feminist backstory Joe
Rowling's rise to success is this sort
of feminist Cinderella story now cruy
besieged by a vicious mob of transgender
activists all because she as a woman had
a few tiny concerns about the
transgender rapists I had been becoming
increasingly concerned about the way in
which women were being shut down women
who I felt had some very valid concerns
Megan uncritically accepts Ring's
framing of the conflict as feminists
versus trans rights activists whom
Rowling describes as a powerful
Insidious misogynistic movement for the
first 5 hours of this podcast Rowling's
critics are presented as an irrational
mob of enraged shrieking sexually
violent Fanatics you are
murdering
children get up a huge amount of I want
her to choke on my fat trans dick and
you did it at my birthday dinner there's
this one clip of some kind of antifa
super soldiers abrasive screaming that
they play like once per episode [ __ ] you
you ugly piece of [ __ ] you fing got your
teeth kned out you [ __ ] Frist nobody
knows who you are and nobody cares and
you will die alone and then it usually
cuts to like somber Monks chanting some
kind of medieval lament you will die
alone and you will burn in
hell just in case you didn't get from
the ti that this is a Witch
[Music]
Hunt do you guys get it do you get it
yet got your teethed out you [ __ ]
trist get up and then these mobs of
irrational misogynistic trans rights
Fanatics are contrasted with this
poignant story of how JK Rowling escaped
her abusive husband to publish our gener
generation's most beloved novels I was
still very committed to those parts that
I plotted in darkness as it were because
there was a truth to them and there was
a power to them the only voices of
genuine trans descent appear in episode
6 out of seven more than 5 hours in and
there's only two of us one is
me shame and the other is a teenager
named Noah who kind of just seems like
he wants to be liked and understood and
wishes that his favorite author would
please stop saying bigoted things about
him I'm such a big Harry Potter fan or I
was such a big Harry Potter fan
especially because it was so hard to be
in the real world I can't even State how
important it was to me shk Rowling I
stole her biography from my third grade
classroom and I kept it for a long time
cuz I just loved reading it cuz I just
admired her so much it's honestly pretty
heartbreaking to listen to on my last
day editing this video I got in touch
with Noah I asked him if he had any
thoughts about the podcast he wanted me
to pass along and this is what he said I
want to emphasize that the stakes of
this issue are very different from any
sort of rhetorical debate conversation
dialogue and debate are important but
for many of the most vulnerable people
in society the outcome of this
conversation dictates their health
well-being and ability to survive how we
treat or talk to people like JK Rowling
should come second to fighting for
maintained access to healthcare support
support and general resources for
children and Adolescent seeking gender
care I agree the most frustrating thing
about this podcast is that it refuses to
be honest about what it is they spend 7
hours implying that JK Rowling is the
victim of a Witch Hunt in the most heavy
handed way imaginable these are the
Witch Trials of JK
rolling I mean Turf is basically witch
but if you point this out they just deny
it show me the actual words sh Show me
where I said I'm the victim of a Witch
Hunt by trans people you're on a podcast
called The Witch Trials of JK Rowling
yes a podcast on which I never once say
I'm a victim of a Witch Hunt by trans
people what are you talking about I'm
not scamming the government if that's
what you're saying your license plate
says scamming uh no what do you mean
no yes Joanne show me where I ever said
that I'm the target of a Witch Hunt you
liar
why would you even think that you're
crazy by the way come get your this
which doesn't burn t-shirt for sale now
at wild woman workshop and Megan is not
much better like there's this whole
section in episode 2 where Megan
interviews Christians who burned Harry
Potter books in the 1990s and this is
obviously meant to be foreshadowing so
looking back would you say that the
Christian parents were maybe part of a
moral panic yeah absolutely it's a Scary
World out there Megan doesn't explicitly
say she thinks trans protests against
Joe row are equivalent to the Christian
ones in the 9s but she does heavily
imply it there was an explosive reaction
to Rowling's tweets which led many
including lifelong fans of her work to
condemn her and to call for her books to
be banned boycotted and in some cases
burned when confronted about the obvious
implications of the podcast's title
Megan said the title is ambiguous toward
the end of our conversations I spent a
long time talking with JK Rowling about
discernment about how a person can ever
know if they're standing up for what
right or joining a moral panic I think
you'll be surprised by the thoughts she
shares
Megan I was not surprised I know I won't
ever regret having stood up on this
issue ever the podcast released new
episodes weekly and whenever Megan was
challenged about the blatant
one-sidedness Megan would respond oh you
just think that because you haven't
listened to the whole podcast yet maybe
you should preserve judgment much more
of other perspectives is coming make
sure to tune in next week more bombshell
Revelations to come well I've listened
to the whole podcast now and I truly do
not think that anyone with basic media
comprehensions skills could come away
from this thinking that the main intent
was anything other than to portray JK
Rowling as the marter of an
unjust
uh what's the word Witch Hunt this is
the obvious implication of the podcast
from the first words to the very last
and of course rolling does literally get
the last word the final episode
concludes with this there are more
important things in this world than
being
popular and that doesn't mean it's more
important to me to be right it means
it's more important to me to do the
right thing why would you end on that
note why would anything about this
podcast be the way it is if Megan didn't
fundamentally believe that JK Rowling is
in the right I don't regret it because I
did the right thing like there really is
no other reasonable way to interpret
this so I wish that she would just be
honest if you believe that JK is the
Misunderstood victim of a Witch Hunt
then just say that make the argument you
want to make don't Crouch and hide
behind this disavow this obfuscating
veil of just asking questions don't rely
on inuendo and Framing and lack foros
Gregorian chanting to make your point
while coily denying you have any kind of
agenda Beyond I just believe in convers
ation I don't know I just find this a
slippery and dishonest way to argue but
if you happen to be a fan of slippery
and dishonest arguments you're in luck
because there is more where that came
from this video is sponsored by canab
box canab box offers fresh human meat
delivered directly to your doorstep as
an alphabet mafiosa sometimes I just
can't fit the most dangerous game into
my busy lifestyle of destroying the
family and recruiting children whenever
a new box arrives I get out my copy of
bless this food the Anita Bryant family
cookbook the best thing about human meat
delivered to your home by mail in the
dead of night you don't know who you're
eating so it's totally guilt-free and
ethically sourced maybe there's no
ethical consumption under capitalism
that means you're not allowed to canel
me chapter 4 Joe Rose
transphobia that's it
I'm going full Slytherin in episode five
of The Witch Trials of JK rolling Joo
Compares trans activists to Death Eaters
the fictionalized fascists in Harry
Potter my position is that this activist
movement in the form that it's currently
taking Echoes the very thing that I was
warning against in Harry Potter the
death eat has claimed we have been made
to live in secret and now is our time I
am fighting what I see as a powerful
Insidious misogynistic movement when an
article then claimed she had equated
trans people to death theaters the
podcast's pr firm reached out demanding
a correction because she only equated
the movement to death theaters not trans
people in general yeah I don't hate
marginalized people I just hate it when
they advocate for themselves so I do
have to be very careful with my wording
here lest a defamation letter arrive by
Owl JK Ring's bigotry is exhausting to
argue with because she expresses it as
an endless series of what are called M
and Bailey arguments a m and Bailey
argument is named after a type of Castle
consisting of a Mot that is a tower at
top of Mound or Hill easy to defend and
a Bailey a fenced Courtyard that's much
more vulnerable to attack difficult to
defend so a motten Bailey argument is
when someone makes a provocative claim
that's difficult to defend the Bailey
and then when confronted with counter
arguments they walk it back to a much
less controversial and easy to defend
version of the claim the mot for example
Rowling will make an ambiguous claim
like sex is real what does she mean by
that what are the implications well in
the podcast she explains that she thinks
it's very Sinister that in the
Associated Press style guide it says
that instead of referring to a
transwoman as a man who identifies as a
woman journalists should simply say say
a transwoman is a woman that from the
Associated Press is hugely powerful
they've edged from identifies as a woman
so a man identifies as a woman which and
I think we all understand what that
means into is a woman and that's
precisely the creep that I'm talking
about we are using language to make
accurate definition of sex
difference unspeakable which is of
course false because the words trans and
CIS exist precisely to make it easy to
talk about sex difference thanks a lot
Tumblr God there's this whole section of
the podcast that sort of implies that
transgender people were invented on
Tumblr which I'm not even going to get
into because we don't have time roling
has also tweeted that she thinks that
all people who menstruate must be
referred to as women or was it Wen I'm
pretty sure it was wump mud so trans men
and trans masculine people they're all
women and must be referred to as women
because JK Rowling demands it this is
controversial right calling trans women
men who identify as women calling
transmen women this is the Bailey in her
ma and Bailey argument trans women are
men trans men are women that's the
controversial interpretation of sex is
real now when accused of transphobia and
facing backlash Rowling walks the
argument back and says I'm being
persecuted just for saying that women
should be allowed to discuss how being
female has shed shaped our lives women
female has shaped our lives this is the
obvious and utterly uncontroversial
interpretation of sex is real the m and
virtually every argument sophisticated
transphobes make about trans people
follows this pattern JK Ring's friend
and Ally Maya forat will tweet
inflammatory things like men cannot
change into women but then when she's
criticized she'll say that she's being
attacked for gender critical belief
gender critical belief which is the
absolutely ordinary belief about sex
that your mother and your grandmother
are women being female is a thing your
mother and grandmother are women being
female is a thing that's literally all
I'm saying but if that's literally all
she was saying then no one would be mad
would they nine Nar men cannot change
into women is the Bailey your mom is a
woman is the mod your mom's a
woman this is why arguing with these
people is infuriating they'll insinuate
that trans women are dangerous rapists
exhibitionists and vur then when trans
people understandably get mad they'll
say look I'm being attacked just for
saying that being female is part of my
experience it's dishonest they talk a
bunch of trash about trans people and
then when trans people talk trash back
they pretend that they're being
victimized for making totally innocuous
statements we can name this Behavior the
birthday boy argument I dated a 58 guy
who taunt every jacked 63 bro he met
until they'd pull their fist back to
beat him up whereupon my ex would go hey
hey hey come on I'm a little guy I'm
just a little guy no it's also my
birthday I'm a little birthday boy and
somehow it always worked so a birthday
boy argument is when you make aggressive
inflammatory assertions followed by
teacher teacher look what he's doing to
me when the target reacts with anything
less than extreme politeness another
common tactic you'll see anytime
Rowling's transphobia is discussed is
you'll see someone jump in to say show
me one thing she's said that's
transphobic for example here's someone
on Twitter called large gameit producer
it's funny isn't it how these people
will insist that awkward inclusive
language like people who menstruate is
horribly oppressive and degrading but
then they'll just straight up call
themselves large gam producer which by
the way is Ring's definition of a woman
the woman is um the producer of the
large gamits oh I like it it's very
brood mother that Rowling's words
regularly appear in gender critical
arguments shows the massive influence
that she has in the anti-trans movement
she's like their Queen they their their
leader their their head mistress she's
the best thing that ever happened to
them cuz Sheila Jeff certainly wasn't
persuading a lot of people if you know
you know large gamet producer says JK
isn't anti-trans give me just one direct
quote that she has said which is
anti-trans oh what's that you can't find
one well Color Me shocked imagine before
we waste our time trying to provide
examples let's take a look at large gam
producers profile trans women are not
women they are men trans men are not men
they are women nothing can change that
sex is
binary like if this person doesn't think
that trans women are men trans men are
women is a transphobic statement then
what would they consider a transphobic
statement this is why the first question
you should always ask such people is do
you believe that transphobia is a
legitimate concept what are some
examples of statements that you would
consider transphobic because many of
them don't believe that transphobia is a
valid concept because they don't think
that trans people are a legitimate
minority there's no such thing as a
transom there's no such thing as a trans
person there is no such thing there are
people that call themselves these things
that may have other issues manifesting
that then make them think they're this
but no we have to stop using any words
like transgender there may be more words
that we have to say in order to say that
we may call it transgender ideology uh
but when it comes to a person they may
be following transgender ideology but
they are not transgender there is no
such thing as a man or a woman being
anything other than a man or a woman so
when they say show me an example of
something transphobic JK Rowling has
said this is a trap they're just mess
ING with you there's nothing that she
could have said that they would
acknowledge as transphobic now if you're
someone who believes that transphobia is
a valid concept and you believe that
trans people are a legitimate minority
but you just genuinely are unaware of
what JK Rowling has said on the topic
then I will refer you to my past video
on JK Ring's transphobia rather than
recapping it all here just keep in mind
that she's gotten significantly worse
since I made that video I mean just look
at her Twitter feed true she never says
the phrase I hate trans people people
because she's not a complete idiot but
Anita Bryant never said I hate gay
people she said save our children I love
her with sexual for that matter I'm
pretty sure David Duke doesn't say I
hate black people but he will share a
lot of statistics about anti-white crime
so this is not really a very good
Criterion for deciding who's a bigot is
it what JK ring does do is tweet again
and again about transgender rapists
about the danger trans women posed to
CIS women she implies that trans
inclusive language is equivalent to the
dystopia of Orwell's 1984 she writes at
length about the vague nefarious cabal
of endocrinologists and ideologues that
is supposedly persuading confused
vulnerable girls to transition to quote
Washington Post opinion writer Monica
hes I do not know what is in Ring's
heart but reading her Twitter feed this
is the overall effect her Twitter feed
does not ask its readers to think it
asks them to fear it creates phobias of
trans people it creates trans
phobias if you will Rowling has also
attacked protr politician Nicholas
sturgeon calling her destroyer of
women's rights via a t-shirt she got
from anti-trans heat Monger posie Parker
there's no such thing as a transom
there's no such thing as a trans person
there is no such thing if there's one
thing that I want people to understand
about Rowling's transphobia it's that
this is is not a casee of someone
posting a couple insensitive tweets that
got blown out of proportion Rowling is
an extremely outspoken opponent of trans
rights this has been her main issue for
several years now and because she's so
famous she's become the de facto Global
champion of backlash to trans rights
truly the Anita Bryant of transphobia
except worse because she's way more
famous and way more liked than Anita
Bryant ever was Rowling has also praised
self-described Theocratic fascist Matt
Walsh for his transphobic propaganda
film she refers to trans women as trans
identified males known as Tims among
people for whom this has become an
unhealthy Obsession she retweets images
of the trans colors being erased from
the progress flag also the colors
representing queer people of color so
you know great love that often roling
pretends that she's being transphobic
for the principled and Valiant purpose
of Defending lesbians it's something of
a fixation for her I find this
particularly gross because it plays into
the lesbophobic Trope that gay women are
especially anti-trans when in fact
they're the least transphobic
demographic of CIS people according to a
survey of young adults in the UK
lesbians were most likely to know a
trans person and also most likely at
96% to say that they're supportive or
very supportive of trans people so I
think it's fair to say that most gay
women are probably not super thrilled
whenever Joe the lesbian Defender logs
on my own partner is a CIS lesbian and I
asked her if she enjoys JK rolling
defending her from the transexuals and
she said it makes me want to gouge out
my eyes like edus by the way here is JK
Rowling enjoying a bit of banter with
her friend baroness Emma Nicholson the
co-founder of Rowling's charity lumos
baroness Nicholson is a conservative
member of the House of Lords who voted
against same-sex marriage in 2013 in
2020 she tweeted in defense of her vote
claiming that gay marriage would lead to
degrading the status of women and girls
truly one of the great lesbian allies
and in 2022 here is JK Rowling joking
around with Lady Nicholson excellent
question Emma defining lesbians as
same-sex attracted women excludes and
depresses the most marginalized of all
groups I.E people with penises and
beards who want to Shag women and before
you say but aren't they straight men
they're wearing eyeliner bigot try for a
moment to put aside any Nostalgia you
may have for the Gryffindor common room
and just look at this interaction for
what it is two straight women one of
whom is a homophobic peer of the realm
having a nice little chuckle together
about how trans women are men wearing
eyeliner so that's it right it's
over case closed
I still like hammering
things I'm not going to argue anymore
about whether JK Rowling is transphobic
because anyone who believes in
transphobia can see that obviously she
is the question now is whether
transphobia is the sort of thing that
progressives can denounce the way we at
least aspire to denounce racism misogyny
and homophobia that's usually what we're
talking about when we talk about JK
rolling right whether it's fair to
cancel her that's what the Witch Trials
of JK rolling is about the rolling
debate is a proxy for a larger question
is transphobia a legitimate Viewpoint
worthy of polite consideration and
respect in Liberal Humane Society or is
it just an ugly Prejudice that we can
justifiably react to with scorn and
condemnation and there's an even broader
question here about whether we can
justifiably react to anything with scorn
and condemnation is cancelling ever
warranted is it right to condemn racism
homophobia and misogyny or should we
allow spokespeople for these prejudices
a respected position in the free
marketpl of ideas where we can all sit
around debating the legitimacy of gay
marriage or the possible merits of a
white ethn state is the final solution a
myth promulgated by the international
Jew are yoga pants to blame for sexual
violence wouldn't the taxpayer save a
lot of money
if there weren't so many disabled people
who knows these are open questions let's
sit down with people on both sides on
many sides and have calm civil
conversations about it for the rest of
our goddamn lives chapter 5
debate Sor I know I did this look before
and it's like not related to the video
Topic at all but it just makes me feel
sliving the boy who sved so Megan Phelps
r Viewpoint seems to be that scorn and
condemnation are never appropriate that
we should approach every conflict with
empathy and compassion even when dealing
with the worst most destructive people
in the world hi my name is Megan and my
heretical belief is that even the people
who seem to be the worst most
destructive people in the world are
human beings who deserve compassion and
empathy if we want to find a way to
change their minds in her book in her
Ted Talk in her public opin appearances
Megan expresses the idea that Society
has recently become polarized in some
unprecedented way that we've all become
extremists that in some sense we've all
become the westbo Baptist Church I can't
help but see in our public discourse so
many of the same destructive impulses
that ruled my former Church she
identifies things like certainty
vilification of compromise US versus
them thinking suppression of empathy and
celebration of death and Misfortune as
Westboro like elements in public
discourse and this really bothers Megan
because she claims that a decade ago
when she went on Twitter to tweet about
how marriage is abominable to God it was
people who engaged her in a civil
rational way that eventually led her to
renouncing West bro's ideology and like
I don't entirely disagree with Megan
about this she's totally right that if
you want to change people's Minds then
approaching them with compassion and
empathy is usually the best way to do
that but Megan reaches another
conclusion that I don't agree with which
is that because compassion and civil
conversation are most likely to persuade
people we should never cancel anyone
even the most horrible bigots and
cancelling is a pretty meaningless term
at this point but when Megan means is we
shouldn't say mean things to bigots we
shouldn't boycott or counter-protest or
or raise our voices we shouldn't shun or
exclude anyone because that's just not
how you change minds and I get why Megan
thinks this right deradicalization was a
really important part of her life
experience she's also clearly holding
out hope that other members of her
family will leave Westboro and have a
life on the outside she has a quote from
her mom in her Twitter bio the last
lines of her book address her family I
want to tell them that I love them I'll
just have to find another way this is
touching and human and also kind of a
conflict of interest the problem is
Megan's views about this only make sense
if you assume that Megan is the main
character of reality if you assume that
the moral Improvement of bigots is more
important than protecting the people
they target or if you assume that
changing bigots Minds is the only way to
make social progress which it isn't as
far as I know Anita Bryant is 83 years
old and she's still homophobic but even
without his Blessing gay rights have
still somehow managed to progress since
the 1970s because gay activists didn't
need to persuade Anita Bryant they
needed to defeat her and that's what
they did we have to accept that
realistically persuading all the bigots
is just not an option yes we should
convince as many people as possible but
there will always be bigots and mocking
them shaming them or boycotting them is
I think a perfect ly valid strategy does
that mean that when we cancel bigots
we're acting kind of like the westbo
Baptist Church n you would only think
that if you're a total moral relativist
I guess controversial opinion but
bigotry is shameful and it should be
shamed I'll say it you know if you're
testing out some racist ideas in your
head you might feel afraid to express
them publicly for fear of being shamed
or judged is that because we live in an
orwellian dystopia that punishes people
for wrong think no it's because racism
is dangerous and shameful and you should
be ashamed of it and the people judging
you are right to do so and sure there
are some very patient people who devote
their lives to Der radicalizing bigots
which I think is a perfectly Noble thing
to do there's a guy named Daryl Davis
who's befriended members of the Klux
clan for over 30 years and he claims
he's convinced more than 200 of them to
leave and good for him deradicalization
is a valid strategy but it cannot be the
only strategy and it must not be the
primary strategy because we're not going
to defeat racism by telling black people
to be a little nicer to racists
feminists would be wasting their time
trying to convince Andrew Tate to
respect women in general I think that
the massive effort that it takes to
maybe persuade bigots is better spent
persuading other people not to listen to
them and it's also worth cautioning that
deradicalization is often a messy and
incomplete process 20-year-old white
nationalist Peter saitan ofic became the
face of the fascist unite the right
rally in 2017 when a photo of him midc
scream TIY torch in hand was published
in news outlets all over the country
Peter was unrepentant in interviews he
gave immediately after the rally but he
began to question his beliefs after
befriending a Muslim woman who according
to Charlotte McDonald Gibson challenged
his views without insulting him allowing
him to understand the hurt he had caused
Peter is no longer a white nationalist
but that doesn't mean he's flushed out
every trace of bigotry in a 2019
interview with the London School of
Economics student paper Peter said I
don't like the whole transgender thing
you're born either a man or a woman so
he maybe still has a little bit of work
to do when I did deradicalization work
on YouTube I used to get some criticism
from people of color who were not
thrilled that I was bringing a bunch of
semi- reformed racists over to the left
a frustration that I totally understand
to paraphrase YouTuber Ian dankin
diverse leftist communities are maybe
not the best holding space for someone
who's a bit of a Nazi but working on it
in the case of Megan Phelps Roper I
don't know if she has lingering bigoted
sentiments but what she does have is a
kind of hypervigilant skepticism about
anything she perceives as ideology this
is pretty common with people who used to
be religious fundamentalists they were
so certain they were right only to
realize that everything they believed
about the world is wrong so they become
distrustful of any strong moral
convictions because it reminds them of
their former fanaticism coming from
westbo where I believed so strongly that
I was doing the right thing and then
tell believe and come to believe that it
was so destructive and
harmful I had this this moment in time
and it lasted for for many months where
I was like how can I ever trust my own
mind again this kind of skepticism is in
some ways a good impulse but valuing
dispassionate intellectualism above all
else can cause problems especially where
topics of social justice are concerned
because it can lead you to this kind of
toxic centrism that asks why are
marginalized people so unwilling to have
calm philosophical debates about whether
they should have rights are they afraid
of dangerous ideas atheist philosopher
Sam Harris in his podcast about Megan's
podcast can we talk about how there are
too many podcasts I'm calling for a
complete and total shutdown of podcasts
until we can figure out what's going on
Sam Harris in his podcast about Megan's
podcast complained that transactive ISM
and activism in general is plagued by
mental illness and hysteria I frankly
think there there's a fair degree of of
mental instability and and even Frank
mental illness in the activist Community
I mean in in in really in all activist
communities the level of viciousness and
hysteria is um you know it's hard to
know what to compare it to diversity
when man accuses trans women of being
hysterical is it really hysteria to
react with strong emotions when your
basic inclusion in society is Up For
Debate aren't there certain situations
where strong emotions are warranted it
reminds me of this awful episode of Joe
Rogan feat Ben Shapiro where Lil Benny
argues that gay marriage is immoral with
his usual whining sophistry and Joe
gently raises objections for Ben to talk
circles around the human sex drive was
made to procreate within a stable
relationship in order to progenerate and
have future generations of people misuse
of that sex drive in any way whether
you're talking about from masturbation
to homosexual activity is therefore a
diminishment of the use of that drive
that's the natural law case against
against homosexual activity all of the
top comments on this video are like this
imagine talking about different beliefs
while still having a productive
conversation things progress when you
don't demonize people the discussion
here was excellent two guys with
opposing opinions speaking calmly and
intellectually without cursing shouting
and making disparaging comments about
each other this is how it should be done
kudos to both of them Joe is a great
interviewer he can totally disagree with
someone and still have a calm Collective
conversation this is how it should be
just two people sharing ideas learning
different point of views from each other
this is why Joe is the number one
podcast Joe Rogan beautifully asked the
tough questions and Ben answers honestly
he is strong in his faith I love this
debate because it's two so contrasting
views and they have a conversation great
learning and like yeah it's easy for two
straight men to have a dispassionate
theoretical conversation about the
ethics of homosexuality because it's not
their lives and their relationships that
are up for debate these people don't
understand the emotional burden placed
on marginalized people who are asked to
defend their rights like if you're
straight do you want to publicly debate
whether your marriage is valid Andrew
dworin claimed that penetrative
heterosexual intercourse is inherently
an act of violence I've noticed that
most straight men don't want to have a
calm civil conversation about that so
imagine how they'd react if there was a
powerful political movement to
criminalize penetration or revoke their
right to marry add in a lifetime of
ostracism family rejection bullying and
discrimination and maybe then you'll
begin to understand the hysteria of a
lot of queer people it is is my right to
raise my child with the moral precept
that I find to be beneficial for my
child bet work does not get to raise my
child and if he tries I will meet him at
the door with a gun that is insane wow
Ben Shapiro threatening violence because
he can't handle the debate sounds like a
classic case of Hysteria to me why can't
Ben Shapiro just have a polite
conversation about boric transing his
children I now have two choices one is
to leave the country utterly two is to
pick up a gun those are the only choices
that you have left me Dave Ruben is a
gay conservative whose career requires
that he convince his right-wing audience
that he's one of the good ones this
means that he's willing to sit across
from his so-called friend homophobe Ben
Shapiro and listen to Ben say he would
never attend his anniversary party
because it would be tantamount to
endorsing sin there's a difference
between me just being friends with Dave
and me actively participating in an
event
that I feel is religiously sinful the
two of them then congratulate themselves
about how they can still be great
friends why is it that we're able to do
this and most people can't do this
that's what I'm curious we go home at
night and we can have our own lives and
here's Dave having a civil conversation
with conservative Glenn Beck who
Compares homosexuality to alcoholism and
then congratulates himself on having the
conversation I am a deeply religious man
and my religion says
man and a woman uh that is the basic
building block of family and that's what
I believe but I also am I also I also
know God created you just like he
created me Flaws and All uh you know um
I believe I have a gene they've never
found it that makes me very susceptible
to alcoholism because it runs in my
family so does craziness but it runs my
family well Dave smiles and nods
probably because he's thinking about how
much he enjoys the taste of
boots usually I just take out a picture
of me and DeSantis and then we're good
because they get it they get it that's
my Governor yeah I think a lot of
straight people look at Dave ruin and
they see finally a reasonable gay person
who doesn't scream bigot at everyone who
disagrees and can actually have a civil
conversation but that's not what I see I
look at Dave Ruben and I see a sainless
boot looking doormat who won't even
defend his own family from the most
fundamental disrespect I also can't help
but notice that none of these civil
conversations seem to change anyone's
mind persuasion is more complicated and
less rational than people think Megan
often says that she was deradicalized on
Twitter but if you read read her book
carefully you'll notice that that's not
exactly true the major precipitating
event for Megan's crisis of Faith was
her mother's mistreatment at the hands
of an increasingly misogynistic Church
leadership that made Megan feel like she
was the victim of the church for once
she says of the church discipline for
the first time in my life the accus were
people I lived with and knew most
intimately and I knew that the judgments
leveled by the elders were wrong I could
no longer blindly trust the Judgment of
these men so she finally experienced
firsthand what it's like to be the
victim of her family she stopped voting
for The leopards eating people's faces
party only when the leopards ate her
face it also seems relevant to notice
that the people who had calm civil
conversations with Megan on Twitter were
generally not gay people the people most
affected by her family's violent
rhetoric they're mostly straight men
like director Kevin Smith who started #
saave Megan because quote she's hot
there's often an neotic component to
persuasion and that certainly seems to
be the case with Megan because one of
the people who helped deradicalize her
is now her husband and I feel like
that's IR relevant detail if we're
trying to understand the role of reason
and emotion in deradicalization
experiences I think this experience is
usually more akin to religious confir
verion than it is to logical reasoning
there's also a world of difference
between the mostly private conversations
that actually lead people to reflect on
their beliefs and the spectacle of
public debate Ben Shapiro is never going
to become less homophobic because he
live streamed a civil conversation with
Dave Ruben so who is this conversation
even for well obviously it's for the
audience I think these civil
conversations basically function to to
reassure a homophobic audience that just
because they disagree with the lifestyle
doesn't mean that they hate gay people
look at Ben Shapiro he's friends with a
gay public debate is one way that we
Define the limits of the Overton window
the range of beliefs that is socially
acceptable to hold so often people who
want to promote bigotry will use debate
as a foot in the door it's a way of
establishing that their prejudices are
within the realm of reasonable and
socially accepted opinion here's
obsessive anti-trans bigot Graham
linahan in a fury that a drag queen is
on Doctor Who without the British public
having a proper debate about these
issues now why do we need to have a
proper debate about whether drag queens
should be allowed on television when
drag performance has been a staple of
British entertainment since at least the
time of Shakespeare life is a that's
just be
g fromo fishy fishy fishy fish as I am
man my state is desperate for my
Master's love As I Am
Woman now last the day bigots like
Graham want a Perpetual debate on their
own terms because this is how they
dignify their Pearl clutching it's how
they convince the public that their
moral Panic about drag queens on TV is
actually a valid concern rather than the
tedious small-minded whining about
nothing that it really is having the
debate on a biggest terms is not a good
way to win people over unless you're
really skilled in the art of humiliating
people which most of the time is what
public debate is actually about this is
something that JK Rowling doesn't seem
to understand in the which Trials of JK
ruling Joo takes a contradictory stance
on deplatforming she brings up
right-wing provocator Milo yannopoulos
saying that activists are making a
strategic error and giving Milo Power by
protesting his events making him look
dangerous and sexy but when trans people
try to deplatform turfs Rand
characterizes this as silencing so is
deplatforming a strategic era that gives
power to your opponent or is it a
powerful tactic of silencing I find
Ring's conviction that we ought to
debate Milo yannopoulos really out of
touch milonopoulos doesn't have reasons
for the things he does he has strategies
for humiliating people I've taken some
time out of my busy schedule being
fabulous and doing my hair to prepare a
speech for you well a few remarks
really feminism is cancer thank you very
much to again quote Ian danin you can't
really reason with someone who thinks
that feminism is cancer because you
don't reason with cancer you eradicate
it rolling objects to the slogan no
debate in the strongest possible terms
and then we come to the famous two-word
slogan the stop phrase no debate no
debate no debate we hear it all the time
that alarms me really alarms me I can't
think of a purer instance of
authoritarianism than no debate it's
kind of amazing to me that someone can
think angry trans people on Twitter are
the purest example of authoritarianism I
truly hope that one day I am privileged
enough to be capable of such a
perspective before I move on I do want
to clarify that I do think there are
trans issues that are legitimately
debatable by people who are not bigots
in my opinion trans women in women's
sports is one of those issues but it's a
complicated issue like first of all
which sport are we talking about are we
talking about figure skating Middle
School field hockey I see no reason why
trans girls should be excluded from that
but if we're talking about professional
weightlifting well then it seems
plausible that trans women who have been
through male puberty may still retain
some kind of group Advantage but not all
trans women have experienced male
puberty people are transitioning younger
now and that's another thing you have to
consider so I'm not against debating
this issue I just want people to
approach it with nuance and good faith
and currently a lot of the people who
are vocally against trans women in
women's sports sound like this and we
will keep men out of women's sports
right how
ridiculous that will take place on day
one and I don't want to debate those
people I want to serve them a banana
cream pie chapter 6 illiberal
methods one of JK Ring's core complaints
about the trans Rights Movement is she
sees it as illiberal in its methods so
when I first became interested and then
deeply troubled by what I saw as a
cultural movement that was illiberal in
its methods so what are these illiberal
methods if you are saying this person is
cancelled that is the language of a dict
T it's true cancel culture is exactly
how the Third Reich started first they
canceled the Socialists and I did not
speak out because the hashtag was
trending but maybe we should see what an
actual dictator
thinks you know can't help but wonder
what counts as acceptable activist
methods to an author for whom Hermione
protesting slavery was taking things too
far I am fighting what I see as a
powerful Insidious misogynistic movement
I do not see this particular movement as
either benign or powerless ring seems to
think that the trans Rights Movement is
dangerous and authoritarian in some
unprecedented way that makes it
different from all past Liberation
movements but how what are these
illiberal methods that distinguish trans
rights activism from similar past
movements cancelling Anita Bryant was
way more cancelled than JK Rowling ever
will be boycotts boycotts have been a
staple of every progressive movement in
modern history disrupting feminist
meetings disrupting feminist meetings is
a feminist tradition haven't you heard
of the lavender Menace in 1969 Betty
fedan author of The Feminine Mystique
and founder of the National Organization
for Women women and second wve feminism
in general coined the phrase lavender
menace to describe the threat she
believed that lesbians posed to the
women's movement fedan was worried that
being associated with lesbians would
make it easy to dismiss the movement as
a bunch of Manish manats this
understandably pissed off a bunch of
lesbians who attended the second
Congress to unite women in 1970 to Stage
what used to be known as a zap a
disruptive public protest designed to
draw attention to gay rights issu think
glitter bombing think pies half
aggression half Whimsy like that time
the lesbian Avengers Zapped Rowling's
friend baroness Nicholson's house
demanding that she resign this podcast
has pushed me over the edge centrism has
gone too far and I am now Pro cancel
culture so just as the meeting was
beginning a group of 17 lesbians wearing
lavender Menace t-shirts Switched Off
the Lights pulled the plug on the mic
and charged down the aisles laughing and
screaming their leader Rita May Brown
took the mic and yelled this conference
won't proceed until we talk about
lesbians and the women's movement one of
the now organizers yelled back I object
to your coming in and taking over this
meeting you're acting like men Betty fan
would later speculate that the lesbians
were a CIA scop designed to make the
women's movement look bad so the
lavender Menace disrupted the feminist
meeting using illiberal tactics not
because they were against feminism but
because they wanted lesbian exclusionary
feminists to include them it's the same
thing that's happened happening today
when trans people disrupt feminist
meetings as JK Rowling puts it
interestingly neglecting to mention
which feminist meetings these are I was
starting to see activists behaving in a
very aggressive way outside feminist
meetings there was a feminist meeting in
which they were uh banging and kicking
on Windows very threatening there's a
historical obliviousness to Rowling's
idea that trans activists are somehow
more aggressive than similar past
movements like she retweeted a
transphobic gay man called Dennis n
Kavanaugh who says all those gay rights
and AIDS protests I don't remember a
single one where we intimidated or
silenced a woman not a single one not a
single one not a single one not a
single
one Dennis has also tweeted that he
preferred aids to the trans movement and
also uh quote I will [ __ ] nail you to
a wall what you have done to these
innocent children your mutilation of
these little human because they were gay
will be nothing compared to what I to to
what I will do to you legally you think
you are ghouls wait till I deal with you
bastard and I mean to Dennis it's time
to log off Gorge I do Wonder does Dennis
threatening to nail people to a wall
count as illiberal methods I guess JK
ring doesn't think so because she's
never condemned it in fact when Dennis's
Twitter suspension ended she was right
there to welcome him back and she
continues to retweet him I've always
been happy to acknowledge that angry
trans people on Twitter sometimes take
things too far things like death threats
or misogynistic insults I don't support
that and I've called it out in the past
like when the leftist streamer Vos drama
alert who is not trans tweeted at JK
Rowling women be quieter and start
apologizing challenge I called him out
tweeting doing edgy ironic misogyny
while defending trans people magnifies
the grain of Truth in what turfs say
about there being misogyny and
transactivism I tweeted that because I
recognize that if people who are
claiming to speak for you are doing so
in a misogynistic way and if you let
that slide you're going to wake up one
day to find that you're in a
misogynistic movement of course vosch
took the criticism really well
explaining that actually I just didn't
understand the complex tactical
arguments for the moral necessity of
being misogynistic to JK Rowling and
then he accused me of cancel culturing
him while at the same time literally
telling his followers to publicly shame
me the more viewer in the replies being
like that's not what's happening right
here like this is necessary okay
publicly shame her
into changing her mind on this then
bringing up my past struggle with
addiction move you off this site and
into I don't want to bring up the
substance abuse so that pretty much conf
confirmed to me that vosch doesn't
actually care about advocating for Trans
people and just uses trans rights as a
pretext to act like a [ __ ] Dingus I
won't tell you to publicly shame him
though because unlike Vos I would never
sink to that the point I'm trying to
make is I have no qualms about calling
out people on my side whenever they go
too far or cross a line or do stupid
tweets and then man explain to me about
how I don't understand tactical misogyny
idiot but the same cannot be said of JK
Rowling I have never once seen her call
out any of the bigotry and abusiveness
that is absolutely rampant in the gender
critical movement there's a great video
called JK Rowling's new friends by
YouTuber Shan that exposes the
dishonesty of framing this conflict as
Meek concerned feminists versus the
abusive trans mob a framing that the
Witch Trials of JK ruling accepts
uncritically citing numerous examples of
death threats and abusiveness from trans
Advocates things like kill turfs 2014
how about slowly and horrendously murder
turfs in saw like torture machines and
Contraptions now I don't think anyone
should joke about putting people in Saw
traps but also how serious is this
threat that was posted to Tumblr in 2014
let's use our critical thinking skills
here do you think that jigsaw the
villain from the Saw movies has a Tumblr
account and is threatening turfs or do
you think this was posted by a
14-year-old the podcast cites zero
examples of death threats and
abusiveness from anti-trans bigots and
it's not exactly like you have to dig
deep to find any I can fill the screen
up with examples just from people who JK
Rowling has explicitly supported or
interacted with I will drive you out
into the desert and bury you 9 ft down
one tweet says from a fan of JK Rowling
first I'll set you on fire and piss on
your half alive corpse [ __ ]
transactivism [ __ ] gender ideology and
[ __ ] you another threat from the same
user is so graphically violent and sex
ual I don't know if I can even read it
aloud without violating the YouTube
terms of service but threats like this
from the gender critical side are simply
not mentioned in the Witch Trials of JK
Rowling both Rowling and Megan seem
happy to cherry-pick threatening tweets
and sound bites of shouting protesters
[ __ ] you you ugly piece of [ __ ] you look
like you got your teeth knocked out you
[ __ ] fist as evidence that the trans
movement is dangerous and Insidious to
the core but this exact technique has
been used against literally every
Liberation movement in world history for
example let's consider reclaim the KN
the protest movement against sexual
violence in Britain which first got JK
rolling interested in feminism in the
1970s here's how the guardian Britain's
spineless Centrist paper of note cover
to reclaimed the night protest in 1979
chanting slogans against rape seems
reasonable to promote awareness but what
about the hissing and swearing at any
innocent male and cries of castrate men
we were all sympathetic to the
principles of the women's Liberation
movement but we left the crowd of
shouting torch bearing women when it
became clear that my friend's brother
was running the risk of personal
mutilation if he remained with us the
protesters were allegedly singing here I
stand my knife in hand free castration
on demand so this is how the British
press covered the women's movement angry
torch bearing women screaming castrate
men now is that a fig representation of
the women's movement should we judge
every Movement by its most militant
extremists is it fair say to pretend
that Valerie solanis who shot Andy
Warhol who advocated for male
extermination in her Society for cutting
up men Manifesto is representative of
feminism as a whole many anti-feminists
over the years have done exactly that
but it's not fair is it so why does JK
rlling think it's fair to judge the
trans Movement by the worst things trans
people have ever tweeted I want her to
choke on my fat trans dick and I made
excuses for you Z in the fourth episode
of The Witch Trials of JK rolling Megan
interviews New York Times columnist
Michelle Goldberg who has written
sympathetically about transphobic
feminism there's a moment in this
interview where Michelle kind of
stumbles into an honest observation that
I find fascinating right I mean I think
you'll often hear people say you know
I'm not going to debate my basic
humanity and and part of the difficulty
is that there are indeed certain issues
which we have sort of decided somewhat
collectively with some sort of consensus
are beyond the realm of of debate and I
think that part of what is so difficult
about this issue is that there are
certain people who think that this kind
of consensus can be imposed maybe as
opposed to evolve
organically and so they're sort of
desperately trying to shore it up in the
hopes I think that if they can they will
enjoy the same sort of assumed
protection ction as other groups whose
rights we've decided are not up
for public conversation I think the
problem is that we don't actually have a
consensus so Michelle correctly observes
that the reason trans people are often
reluctant to debate our rights is that
we want the same assumed protections as
other groups whose rights liberals have
decided are not up for debate but then
Michelle suggests that trans people have
to debate our rights because there isn't
a mainstream consensus that we deserve
rights I am really curious to know how
Michelle Goldberg thinks that past
Liberation movements have succeeded like
does she think that women's suffrage
just evolved organically did
suffragettes just have calm civil
conversations about whether women are
intellectually capable of voting until
all the misogynists were rationally
persuaded no they stood up and demanded
their right to vote sometimes violently
especially in the UK like people forget
this maybe because they were called
suffragettes which is kind of a cute
scen name but the suffragettes they
murdered people they were suffragette
terrorists they broke Windows they
bombed churches they set fire to a
theater in 1909 a suffragette attacked
Winston Churchill with a horse whip
Queen [ __ ] honestly the English
suffragette Mary Lee threw a [ __ ]
Hatchet at the prime minister's head and
my point is not to Advocate terrorism or
to excuse the terrorism of past
movements I think these kinds of tactics
have tended to turn people against the
movement I don't think it's effective
but let's not pretend that past
movements have never made demands before
everyone was ready because there never
has been and there never will be a time
when everyone is ready I mean Mary W
stonecraft published the Vindication of
the rights of women in 1792 and misogyny
in case you hadn't noticed remains
rampant so there never has been a
consensus about women's rights and there
probably never will be in fact
marginalized groups wouldn't need rights
if there was a consensus that we deserve
rights the whole reason to have rights
is to protect you from the kind of
people who think you shouldn't have them
I mean it's a nice thought that we can
just politely persuade everyone to give
us rights but the reality is that's not
how this works and it never has been
like how do these debate me centrists
think that slavery ended in the United
States well between 1861 and
1865 there was a little event called the
American Civil debate see what I'm
holding in my hand this is a high
caliber idea that I picked off the
polite discussion field of Manasses do
you people think that American schools
were integrated because all the white
people in the South were persuaded that
segregation is bad no Dum Dums
Eisenhower had to send in the 101st
Airborne to enforce that [ __ ] at
gunpoint and my point is not to equate
LGBT rights movements with black civil
rights I am aware that being a white
queer person is not in any way
equivalent to living in the aftermath of
slavery I'm just saying that there's
this tendency to sanitize history and to
imagine that progress with smooth and
bloodless that consensus evolved
organically when it just didn't and then
people get the impression that current
movements are somehow more militant than
successful past movements when they just
aren't I am fighting what I see as a
powerful Insidious misogynistic movement
the cultural movement that was illiberal
in its methods and I believe
absolutely that there is something
dangerous about this movement and it
must be challenged why is JK rolling
like this chapter S why is JK rolling
like this JK ring loves to quote radical
feminist Andrea dworin whom I've already
mentioned a couple times in this video I
myself favor violence deeply I favor it
dworin is known for her extreme sex
negative views which I don't agree with
but she wasn't interesting writer one of
those half crazed savants who gets in
your head who you can't stop thinking
thinking about in my opinion doran's
best book is right-wing women published
in 1983 the era of Phyllis schafle and
Anita Bryant right-wing women is an
analysis of why so many women are drawn
to conservative politics seemingly
against their own interests anyone who's
interested in understanding the gender
critical movement a crypto reactionary
backlash disguising itself as feminism
should read this book in dworkin's
analysis the political right makes
certain physical and material promises
to women that both exploit and quiet
some of women's deepest fears no one can
bear to live a meaningless life women
fight for meaning just as women fight
for survival and conservative politics
promises women meaning the right offers
women a simple fixed predetermined
social biological and sexual order form
conquers chaos form banishes confusion
the gender critical movement offers
women a brutally simple understanding of
sex and gender a woman is an adult human
female right-wing anti-trans activist
posie Parker has made this phrase into
the motto of the gender critical
movement adult human female it's on
billboards it's on t-shirts it's on
banners signs and tweets presented with
the authority of a dictionary definition
it's rigid it's orderly it's immutable
there are no Exceptions there are no
Blurred Lines there can be no change
this Mantra is a defense against the
conceptual instability and Chaos that
gender critical fear the same fear that
once drove homophobic women like Anita
Bryant just biologically that God made
mother so that we could reproduce
homosexuals cannot reproduce
biologically erasing the concept of sex
removes the ability of many to
meaningfully discuss their lives dworin
says within the frame of male domination
there is a good reason for women to hate
homosexuality both male and female women
are interchangeable as sex objects women
are slightly less disposable as mothers
the only dignity and value women get is
as mothers having children is the one
social contribution credited to women it
is the Bedrock of women's social worth
without childbearing women know they
have nothing homosexuality for women
means having nothing it means Extinction
substitute transgenderism for
homosexuality and you'll understand the
gender critical movement JK Rowling's
definition of woman is this the woman is
um the producer of the large gametes the
producer of the large gametes roling
says her primary concern about young
trans men is the loss of fertility
homosexuality its rise in public
visibility attempts to socially
legitimize or protect it makes women
Expendable the one thing women can do
and be valued for will no longer be
valued male homosexuality is especially
terrifying because it suggests a world
without women altogether a world in
which women are extinct this exact fear
appears frequently in gender critical
rhetoric trans activists are erasing
women they're erasing biological sex
they're going to call us pregnant people
confused girls are being robbed of their
precious fertility trans women are going
to replace biological women as a woman
woman I feel threatened because
biological men are aggressively
replacing women you will not replace us
sometimes this paranoia ramps up to the
point of obsession and the results can
be dazzling in September 2022 Maya forat
Who you'll remember as the anti-trans
activist whom JK Rowling came out as a
Turf to defend went on a full-blown
Twitter Rampage because the Herford
Shure County Libraries announced they
were changing their children's storytime
mascot from the book start bear if you
don't know where this is going strap in
from the book start bear to a bright
vibrant gender neutral creature called
tala are you
enraged if not you haven't been spending
enough time on mum's net Maya tweeted
the words of an indignant mother who
referred to Talia wait wasn't it tala
referring to Talia as a trans bear with
they them pronouns describing the mascot
as IDE olical creepy and gaslighting I
cannot express how upset I feel the
library jumped in to clarify that tala
not Talia isn't trans they are an alien
Maya then demanded to know how this
alien was birthed did it hatch from an
egg or was it born from a mama some
people tried to reason with Maya there's
an advantage in having a character that
isn't identifiably male or female as it
can be equally relatable to either sex
and avoid promoting stereotypes but Maya
was not convinced it seems highly
unlikely that an alien that had evolved
with such recognizable vertebrate body
plan is not sexually reproducing it's a
relatable anthropomorphic character not
a slime
mold I need to know how the alien [ __ ]
right now I said I need to know how the
alien [ __ ] before I can show it to my
child
when Twitter understandably laughed it
up at Maya's expense she just kept
posting and she posted hard honestly I
don't know if I've ever seen anyone post
so hard in a lengthy diet tribe Maya
wrote about the miseries of new
motherhood you are in charge of a baby
you have never done this before you
haven't had a good night's sleep for
months and won't for years everyone has
an opinion on what you are doing right
and wrong and you've become invisible
you had politics you had had a career
you had interests you had a sex life now
you have the daily needs of a completely
dependent person and your world has
shrunk the fact that these men and the
young women that cheer them on think
this is so laughable reflect society's
disdain from mothers this is what it
means to say a woman is not a feeling or
a costume this is why the Hub of the
resistance is on Mom's net so I am
fascinated by this thread I think it's
one of the most revealing texts in
gender critical history because you know
what Maya forter actually does have
valid concerns but the concerns she has
that are valid have nothing to do with
trans people and they definitely have
nothing to do with an adorable cartoon
alien honestly reading this I have some
concerns concerns like where is Maya's
husband I know she has one isn't raising
children supposed to be a mutual project
no one should have to feel this alone
raising children that is a valid concern
oh my God we actually found one it's
like finding elderado a valid concern a
valid concern isn't what's going on here
that Maya is taking legitimate feelings
of being overburdened and
underappreciated and displacing those
feelings onto transgender people this is
exactly how the gender critical movement
recruits by providing a scapegoat to
frustrated women it's not your husband's
neglect it's not the increasing
automization of society it's not the
indignities of Aging it's tala the
nonbinary alien with its dkeries and
smug Aura of gender neutrality mom's net
is the Hub of the resistance to
non-binary cartoons it's too much these
people are too much okay we have to be
serious now the political right also
promises women Safety and Security for
women the world is a very dangerous
place the right acknowledges the reality
of d
the validity of fear the right then
manipulates the fear women fear and
resent male violence which they're most
likely to experience from the men
closest to them boyfriends husbands and
fathers they're most likely to be killed
by sexual partners but the need to
survive in a male-dominated society
means that women's legitimate fears and
resentments often cannot be directed at
the men with power inevitably this
causes women to take the rage and
contempt they feel for the men who
actually abused them those close to them
and projected onto others those far away
foreign or different and this
displacement of rage is just
transparently what's going on with JK
Rowling in her essay about sex and
gender issues Rowling speculates that
trans men are transitioning to be the
son her father wanted I really felt the
rejection of my father and that is one
of the things that maybe lead someone
going into homosexuality and she
describes the lingering Trauma from her
first violent marriage the marriage at
this point has turned very violent and
very controlling and that she says is
why she decided to speak out against the
transgender movement if you try to
understand this rationally it looks like
a total non Secor but if you look at it
emotionally there's a kind of logic to
it the existence of the dangerous
Outsider always functions for women
simultaneously as deception diversion
pain killer and threat women cling to
irrational hatreds focused particularly
on the unfamiliar so that they will not
murder their fathers husbands Sons
Brothers lovers the men with whom they
are intimate those who do hurt them in
the 1970s many conservative women
displaced this rage onto lesbians the
threatening Outsider of the day dorin
attended the National Women's Conference
in 1977 where she spoke to a lot of
women about their fear of lesbians
right-wing women consistently spoke to
me about lesbians as if lesbians were
rapists certified committers of sexual
assault against women and girls to them
the lesbian was inherently monstrous
experienced almost as a demonic sexual
Force hovering closer and closer she was
the dangerous Intruder encroaching
threatening by her very presence a
sexual order that cannot bear scrutiny
or withstand challenge is almost surreal
to read this because of how precisely it
describes how gender criticals talk
about trans women pronouns are like
Rohypnol they dull your defenses they
change your inhibitions they're meant to
now it's true that trans exclusionary
radical feminism began as an offshoot of
far-left lesbian separatism with
academic feminist Janice Raymond writing
in 1979 that transsexualism should be
morally mandated out of existence but
the gender critical movement was always
destined to be become a right-wing
movement because it has the structure of
a right-wing movement taking women's
fear and rage toward familiar men and
displacing it onto an unfamiliar
Outsider the momentum behind this is
just too ripe an opportunity for
conservatives to pass up as dworin says
because women so displace their rage
they are easily controlled and
manipulated haters women require symbols
of danger that justify Their Fear the
right provides these symbols of danger
by designating clearly defined groups of
Outsiders as sources of danger in the
2020s anti-trans bigotry has become a
key Stone of conservative party
platforms both in the UK where Lee
Anderson Deputy chair of the
conservative party predicts that the
next election will be won on probably be
a c mix of culture wars and trans
debates and in the US where the ACLU is
currently tracking more than 450
anti-lgbt bills including more than 130
gender affirming care bands 51 trans
Sports bans 40 drag bands 29 trans b
band and 21 bands defining trans people
out of the law Republicans have
escalated anti-trans rhetoric to
eliminationist extremes that have most
trans people in this country living in a
constant state of fear for our future
transgenderism must be eradicated from
public life entirely the left is
attacking our children pushing sex
transgender extremism and noxious
politics in our schools we should reject
this demonic assault on the innocence of
our children and Stand Fast against
leftist efforts to mutilate their bodies
and Minds stop confusing our babies with
your groomer gender ideologue I will
revoke every Biden policy promoting the
chemical castration and sexual
muiz of our youth
and ask Congress to send me a bill
prohibiting child sexual
mutilation in all 50 states on day one I
will revoke Joe Biden's cruel policies
on so-called gender affirming care
ridiculous I will sign a new executive
order instructing every Federal agency
to cease all programs that promote the
concept of sex and gender transition at
any age a few gender critical
still want to insist they have nothing
to do with right-wing anti-trans vots
like Helen Lewis I mean Turf is
basically witch who attempts in her
interview in The Witch Trials of JK
Rowling to distinguish between the
transphobia of the far right and that of
feminists I think the hardest thing for
Outsiders to understand is that there
are two different arguments going on one
is the traditional conservative right
argument which is anti-lgbt the other
one is a criticism from the left in
which it says
say sometimes male people and female
people have different interests no
matter how the male people identify but
as a transperson I don't care whether
you justify your transphobia in the name
of protecting women or protecting
children whether it's radical feminist
Janice Raymond calling for
transsexualism to be morally mandated
out of existence or conservative
Catholic Michael noes calling for
transgenderism to be eradicated from
public life is the same repulsive
bigotry to me and in any case the gender
critical movement has recently reached
an implicit consensus that they're
mostly done pretending to be feminist
the rising star of the movement posie
Parker AKA Kelly J Kean Mitchell rejects
feminism entirely do you call yourself a
femous now did you ever call yourself a
I probably did for a short time but so
you wouldn't be so like a Julie bindle
type feminist no well some feminists I
mean Julie bindle has been critical of
um mothers in the past and I think
that's a that's a theme flowing through
feminism I'm not a feminist I'm not a
feminist this is not Andrea dworin this
is Phyllis schafle Parker's campaign is
currently funded by the right-wing CPAC
CPAC came along and said that they would
sponsor our events and cover all of our
insurance throughout our whole trip uh
which is really kind of them um but what
we would need to do is we would need to
show that we were working for them
working with them she had has no qualms
about collaborating with far-right
weight nationalists I want to talk about
Marjorie Taylor green let me tell you
what she's been saying she's a
republican but she uh I agree with her
wholeheartedly she's opposed abortion
and contraception for teenagers why are
we enabling um children to take um
sometimes contraceptives that that are
quite harmful or access to abortion um I
think that we really need to rethink all
of this I think parents need to take
back control of their children she's
called trans people fools and perverts
transgenderism is nuts it's for fools
and perverts she's denied that
transgender is a legitimate concept it's
not a real thing there's no such thing
as being born in the wrong body there's
no such thing as a trans woman there's
no such thing as a trans person there is
no such thing there are people that call
themselves these things that may have
other issues manifest ing that then make
them think they're this but no we have
to stop using any words like transgender
um you know there may be more words that
we have to say in order to say that we
may call it transgender ideology uh but
when it comes to a person they may be
following transgender ideology but they
are not transgender there is no such
thing as a man or a woman being anything
other than a man or a woman she's called
trans women pedophiles we know that if a
man has a paraphilia of dressing as a
woman the most likely cross par pilia is
pedophilia we know that these men have
multiple paraphilia they don't ever stop
at one she said that each and every
woman who stands in her way will be
annihilated each and every one of you
women who stand in my way each and every
one of you let me just tell you you will
be annihilated she's called on armed men
to enter women's restrooms to attack
anyone they perceive as not a real woman
and men for one
I'm talking to
you I'm talking about you dads who maybe
carry I think that's what you say uh I'm
so down with the American lingo maybe
you carry maybe you don't uh maybe you
consider yourself a protector of women
maybe you're that sort of man um maybe
you have a daughter or a mother or a
wife uh maybe you have a sister maybe
you just have some friends maybe you
just think women are human and you don't
need any absolute connection with them
to feel compelled to protect
us um I think you should start using
women's toilets men and she said that
women who call themselves men should be
sterilized which seems to be a little
bit in tension with JK Ring's concern
about the fertility of confused girls
you know you might look at these
differences of opinion between Rowling
and Parker little things like pro-
feminist versus anti- feminist left
versus right pro-abortion versus
anti-abortion concern about trans men's
fertility versus advocating forced
sterilization of trans men against
annihilating women who stand in your way
versus Pro annihilating each and every
woman who stands in your way you might
look at these differences and expect
that these two women would be at odds
but they aren't because promoting
anti-trans bigotry is a common cause
that for both of them trumps all else in
2020 posie Parker paid for a poster
reading ihart JK rolling to be displayed
at a railway station in Edinburgh and
Rowling has tweeted in defense of Parker
numerous times and has modeled her
t-shirts so the gender critical movement
started by lesbian separatists in the
1970s has finally passed into the hands
of pound shop Ava Browns as gender
critical lesbian Julie bindle met
memorably described them it's a movement
that has no beliefs apart from a shared
determination to reduce the number of
trans people in the numbers we're
currently seeing particularly of young
people coming forward I find cause for
doubt in the meantime why why we're
trying to get through to the decision
makers we have to try to limit the harm
and that means reducing or keeping down
the number of people who transition and
that's for two reasons one of them is
that every one of those people is a
person who's been damaged
but the second one is every one of those
people is
basically you know a huge problem to a
sane world like if you've got people
that and whether they're transitioned
whether they're happily transitioned
whether they're unhappily transitioned
whether they''re detransitioned if
you've got people who've dissociated
from their sex in some way every one of
those people is someone who needs
special accommodation in a sane world
where we Rea knowledge the the truth of
sex so to wrap this up is the backlash
against against JK rolling a Witch
Hunt unequivocally no it's very
thoroughly deserved but I will say this
a movement can't get along without a
devil and across the whole political
Spectrum there's a misogynistic tendency
to choose a female devil whether it's
Anita Bryant Hillary Clinton Marie
Antoinette Alexandria oazo Cortez or JK
Rowling and there's always going to be
people who seize on any opportunity to
be misogynistic so I would advise trans
people and our allies to keep in mind
that JK Rowling is not the final boss of
transphobia she's not our devil the
devil is the Republican Party the
conservative party the devil is
patriarchy it's the right-wing men who
will be the ones to put gender critical
theory into brutal practice Anita Bryant
posie Parker and JK Rowling are to
borrow a term from turf
handmaidens turfs are the real
handmaidens they're useful idiots who
put a concerned female face on the
patriarchal violence against trans
people that will ultimately be enacted
by right-wing men I call on men to
consider themselves decent human beings
to call out the Deviant among them and
eradicate these monsters from
society and Megan Phelps Roper and
centrists like her are wrong that civil
conversation can
this call out the among them and
eradicate these monsters from
society people like Michael nolles and
Ronda santis and Donald Trump cannot be
persuaded they have to be defeated as
for what to do about JK ring honestly
let's all just block her open up Twitter
right now go to her profile and just
block her problem solved like don't
harass her that doesn't help but also I
wouldn't wait for her to change she's
gone down what I call the bigotry
Whirlpool the deeper you go in the
harder it is to leave for the same
reasons that it's hard to quit a cult or
scam to quote video essayist Dan Olen
one of the most Insidious elements of a
confidence scam is that the victims who
invested the most are often the most
passionate Defenders because shame is a
powerful force in the human psyche and
they can't bear the shame of admitting
they were tricked reformed bigots have
to face not only the shame of being
duped
but also the guilt of having devoted
years of life to harming vulnerable
people this is something Megan to her
credit faced head on if we were wrong
then I had spent every day of my life
industriously sewing Doom Discord and
rage to so many not at the beest of God
but of my grandfather I had wasted my
life only to fill others with pain and
misery most bigots cannot stand to face
this moral sunk cost it's why an
obsessive bigot like Graham linahan who
whose allc consuming hatred of trans
people has ruined his life caused him
his marriage and left him alone to tweet
about destroying gender ideology minutes
before midnight on New Year's Eve feels
psychologically compelled to insist with
ever more certainty that trans people
are not just delusional or dangerous but
are all demonic perverts an enemy so
hyperbolically evil that they justify
his self- ulating
crued they took everything from me you
know they took my
he took my f my family you know I just
said no hang on a sec stop calling these
women turfs stop sending them abuse let
them speak and for that they they just
destroyed me do you honestly feel
destroyed no because because the one
thing about this the one thing about
this that keeps me going is that I know
I'm right you know I know I'm right as
long as he stays here in the bottom of
the whirlpool he never has to face that
he's ruined his relationships and Wasted
Years of life because he just couldn't
let it go and if JK rolling doesn't log
off soon this will likely be her fate as
well I guess what I'm really trying to
say is Harry Potter is dead to me I'm
switching to Twilight
[Music]
at least it's a fruit pie